necu.org 2010-11-26

# Northeast Credit Union : Privacy & Security

****

At Northeast Credit Union, the Board of Directors, management and staff make protecting your privacy and web security a priority.

We recognize that preserving your trust includes protecting your personal and financial information. We do not share any information that you provide us with third parties other than what is necessary to provide you with the services or products you have requested, or is required by law, or to protect ourselves against fraud. If you have any questions about our policy, please contact Member Service at 1-888-436-1847.  

**Privacy Notice**  

Northeast Credit Union's single purpose is to provide you with financial products and services to meet your financial goals. We intend to offer you diverse financial services including competitive products made available by our strategic relationships with other institutions or service providers. We believe these are the reasons you do business with Northeast Credit Union. We also believe you do your financial business with us because we have a strong history of protecting our members' privacy.

We are required by law to give you this privacy notice. It describes our policies and practices that protect your privacy and enables us to share information to make available competitive financial products and services. These practices are followed by the credit union. If you have any questions after reading it, please contact us at 1-888-436-1847.

What follows is a description of the information we collect and disclose, including the parties who receive non-public information from us. This notice also explains your right to inform us if you do not want us to disclose certain information about you to other parties.

_Information We Collect About You_

We collect information about you from the following sources:

  * Information we receive from you on applications and other   form(s); 
  * Information about your transactions with us or others including those companies that work closely with us to provide you with diverse financial products and services; 
  * Information we receive from a credit reporting agency; 
  * Information obtained when verifying the information you provide on an application or other form(s), which may be obtained from your current or past employers, or from other institutions where you conduct financial transactions; and 
  * Information we may obtain from consumer purchasing and census data providers to develop competitive marketing programs for our members. 

_Parties Who Receive Information From Us_

We may disclose non-public personal information about you to the following types of third parties:

  * Financial companies such as insurance or mortgage service companies and securities broker-dealers; 
  * Non-financial companies such as consumer reporting agencies, Generations Gold; 
  * Others, such as government entities. Northeast Credit Union and its affiliate XCU Capital Corporation, may also share your non-public personal information with each other as permitted by law. 

_Disclosure of Information to Parties that Provide Services to Us_

We may disclose all of the information we collect, as described above, to companies that perform services on our behalf or to other institutions we have joint marketing agreements with so that we may provide members competitive products and services. We may also disclose non-public personal information about you under circumstances as permitted or required by law. These disclosures typically include information to process transactions on your behalf, conduct the operations of our credit union, follow your instructions as you authorize or protect the security of financial records.

_Disclosure of Information About Former Members_

If you cease to be a member of Northeast Credit Union, we will not share information we have collected about you, except as may be permitted or required by law.

_How We Protect Your Information_

We restrict access to non-public personal information about you to those employees who need to know that information to provide products or services to you. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations to guard your non-public personal information. Our online banking uses some of the most secure forms of online communication available, Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol and user names and passwords. These technologies provide a high level of security and privacy when you access your account information, initiate online transactions or send secure messages.

_What Members Can Do to Help_

Northeast Credit Union is committed to protecting the privacy of its members and customers. You can help by following these simple guidelines:

  * Protect your account numbers, card numbers, PINs (personal identification numbers) and passwords. Never keep your PIN with your ATM card, check or credit card which can provide free access to your accounts if your card is lost or stolen. For help on creating a strong password __click here__. 
  * Use caution when disclosing your account numbers, social security numbers, etc. to other persons. If someone contacts you via telephone or email explaining they are contacting you on behalf of the credit union, and asks for your account number, you should beware. Official credit union staff will have access to your information and will not need to ask for it. 
  * Keep your information current. It is important that we have current information on how to reach you. If we detect potentially fraudulent or unauthorized activity or use of an account, we will attempt to contact you immediately. If your address or phone number changes, please let us know. 
  * Please do not hesitate to call us if you have any questions - we are here to serve you! 

Click here to read about our Identity Theft 911 service - FREE to our checking and credit card members.

_Fair Credit Reporting Act Disclosure_

Northeast Credit Union will comply with restrictions and requirements set forth in the Fair Credit Reporting Act.

**  
Northeast Credit Union Email Security Information**

Northeast Credit Union (NECU) will periodically send emails promoting our products and services or those of our affiliates, to members for whom we have recorded email addresses. All members who receive the marketing emails will have the opportunity to opt out of this service at any time by simply clicking the unsubscribe button, entering your email address on the [_email opt-out page_](http://email.necu.org/o/?co=0786D6C8267C51C6&cid=38762D7FF7A274E108450758E412F251103E8F7CE1A6CF25), emailing Member Services at memberservices@necu.org, or calling us at 1.888.436.1847.  

As a trusted neighbor NECU will never ask you for personal account information via email. In addition, our latest technology allows you to identify authentic NECU emails upon receipt. NECU email’s that come from “Northeast Credit Union” [marketing@email.necu.org](mailto:marketing@email.necu.org) and links within the email will go to an NECU website domain (i.e. necu.org, my.necu.org, etc.), NOT a 3rd party website. View an example of what an email from NECU would look like in the address field, below:

A **unique identification code (UID)** appears near the top right of every email sent to you from NECU’s address. The last 4 digits of your primary membership number assigned by Northeast Credit Union will be used. It will appear as “ **Ending in 1234** ”. This unique identifier will be exclusive for email’s sent to you from NECU marketing. Below is an example of what it will look like: 

NECU members will always be able to confirm any emails authenticity by calling our member service center at 1.888.436.1847. Our member service representatives will be able to verify the email when you provide them with your email address and the unique identification code. In the event your unique identity number does not match our records, the email(s) are likely to be a phishing scam and will be reported. 

_  
Exceptions_

Our Member Service staff members can reply to you or send you emails which are routed through a different server. These generally are responses directly to member inquiries and never contain personal banking information. These emails do not contain the UID. These emails will be from _memberservices@necu.org.    _In addition, when using CyberTel by initially signing up or changing your password, an auto reply email will be sent to you from _memberservices@necu.org_. This is an automated email and also does not contain the UID.   

_  
Additional Information_

We utilize third-party vendors to send some emails to member regarding products, services or information they may need. These vendors are utilized for estatements, alerts, online surveys, events, web polls, and referrals. Emails sent via our third-party vendors are identified as follows:

  * “Northeast Credit Union” _eStatements@mailhost.docuhost-net.com_
  * “Generations Gold” _info@gengold.net  _

Northeast Credit Union may also solicit feedback on how we can better serve our members. To do this we may use forms on our website that might be managed by a third-party vendor. These forms are secured and encrypted when sent to our vendors. Our member service representatives then login to their secure servers and retrieve the information.

**NOTE:** To make sure you receive our important emails, please make sure you've given the above mentioned addresses permission in your email clients such as Outlook, Hotmail, Yahoo, G-Mail, MSN, and NetZero. Sometimes certain keywords are picked up by filtering software and legitimate emails are sent to your spam folder. By allowing our subdomains to come through, you'll be sure to receive NECU messages.

**Contacting Northeast Credit Union**

If you have questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, please contact:

> Northeast Credit Union  
> 100 Borthwick Avenue, PO Box 1240  
> Portsmouth, NH 03802-1240  
> 1-888-436-1847  
> 

If you prefer to communicate through email, contact [memberservices@necu.org](mailto:memberservices@necu.org). Please note that information sent through email is not secure. Please DO NOT SEND CONFIDENTIAL INFORMATION (account number, social security number, PIN number, etc.) through email.
